<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research | IHCIL@OUC</title><link>http://localhost:1313/en/research/</link><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Research</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>http://localhost:1313/media/logo_hu_640f2529517f577a.png</url><title>Research</title><link>http://localhost:1313/en/research/</link></image><item><title>Ocean forecasting</title><link>http://localhost:1313/en/research/ocean-forecasting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/en/research/ocean-forecasting/</guid><description>&lt;style&gt;
/* 仅选中本条目的列表缩略图（右侧小图） */
a[href="http://localhost:1313/en/research/ocean-forecasting/"] &gt; img {
height: 5200px; /* 图片高度：调大变高 */
width: auto; /* 等比缩放；如需固定宽度可写 220px */
object-fit: cover; /* 裁剪/填充：cover 填满可能裁剪；contain 不裁剪可能留白 */
margin-top: 1000; /* 向下为正数，向上为负数 */
margin-left: 0; /* 向右为正数，向左为负数 */
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our research focuses on the core dynamic processes at the ocean-atmosphere interface, with the primary goal of deepening understanding of the generation mechanisms, evolution patterns, and accurate forecasting of key marine meteorological elements.
This field represents a highly interdisciplinary frontier that integrates physical oceanography, meteorology, and marine engineering. We not only investigate how wind drives the generation and development of ocean waves—including the physical mechanisms of wind wave generation, nonlinear interactions, and swell propagation—but also strive to understand the dramatic responses of the marine dynamic environment under the influence of extreme weather systems such as typhoons and extratropical cyclones.</description></item><item><title>Radar Nowcasting</title><link>http://localhost:1313/en/research/radar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/en/research/radar/</guid><description>&lt;br&gt;
The Radar Group is dedicated to deeply integrating cutting-edge artificial intelligence technologies with radar meteorology, with a core research focus on convective storm nowcasting. To address the complex challenges in this field, we are exploring along two innovative paths: on one hand, leveraging large language models (LLM) and related architectures to process massive spatiotemporal data and mine complex patterns of convective storm evolution; on the other hand, targeting the pain point of scarce extreme weather samples, we are specifically developing few-shot learning methods based on small models to achieve efficient and accurate forecasting with minimal samples. In addition, we are conducting research on synthetic radar retrieval, aiming to compensate for observation blind spots through AI algorithms, providing more complete data support for forecasting models, and building a more intelligent and agile extreme weather warning system.</description></item></channel></rss>